For more information: https://dsevero.com

SHORT BIO

Graduate student with 5 terms of experience TAing, 3 years as a Data Scientist in Brazil, and 2 years as a Machine Learning Engineer implementing solutions in PyTorch for healthcare applications. Contributed to open-source projects such as Dask and Dask-ML.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Electrical & Computer Engineering
Master of Applied Science (M.A.Sc.)
Undergraduate Exchange Program (1 year)

Starting Fall 20202013 - 2014

Federal University of Santa Catarina, Brazil

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering

First Class Honours, 99th percentile.

2010 - 2015

AWARDS

Vector Scholarship in Artificial Intelligence Recipient 2020-21 2020

The Vector Scholarship in AI supports the recruitment of top students to AI-related master's programs in Ontario and is valued at \$17,500.

https://vectorinstitute.ai/aimasters

NSERC Applied Research Rapid Response to COVID-19 Grant

Our project titled "Canadian Hospital Simulator For Management of COVID19 Cases and Contact Tracing" was awarded \$75,000.00.

https://www.nserc-crsng.gc.ca/Innovate-Innover/CCI-COVID_eng.asp

Virtual Design Challenge Winner

2019

2020

Won 1st place at the VDC hosted by The University of British Columbia with my paper *Proof of Novelty*. Received a cash prize of \$3,000.

https://github.com/dsevero/Proof-of-Novelty

Student Merit Award and Medal

2015

Graduated with the highest GPA ever obtained (at the time) for my major. Elected "Best Student" by the faculty of Electrical & Electronics Engineering at the Federal University of Santa Catarina.

Science Without Borders Scholarship

2013

Awarded a full scholarship that covered tuition, transportation, necessary materials and living costs to study 2 academic semesters at the University of Toronto.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Federal University of Santa Catarina

Teaching Assistant

Assisted professors by ministering tutorials, preparing lecture materials and helped students individually at regular office hours.

• Communications Theory

Fall and Winter 2015

Amplitude and frequency modulations; multiplexing; noise in communication systems; pulse modulation; analog-to-digital conversion; digital transmission in baseband and passband.

• Introduction to Electronics

Fall and Winter 2013

Operational amplifiers; diodes; the bipolar junction transistor; field effect transistors; optoelectronic components.

• Single-Variable Calculus

Fall 2010

Real-valued functions; limits; continuity; derivatives and applications; definite and indefinite integrals; integration techniques; improper integrals.

CERTI Foundation

2010 - 2013

Intern Programming Instructor

Responsible for the technical training of new and current interns. Created a training course in LabVIEW programming that is still in use as of 2020.

UNPUBLISHED RESEARCH

Severo, Daniel (2019). *Proof of Novelty*. DOI: 10.6084/m9.figshare.10324883. v1. URL: https://figshare.com/articles/preprint/Proof_of_Novelty/10324883/1.

Severo, Daniel et al. (2019). Ward2ICU: A Vital Signs Dataset of Inpatients from the General Ward. arXiv: 1910.00752 [cs.LG].

PROFESSIONAL SERVICE

NeurIPS 2019: Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems $\,$

Reviewer for the Machine Learning for Health (ML4H) workshop.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Dask: Scalable analytics in Python

https://github.com/dask/dask/pulls?q=author:dsevero

Dask-ML: Scalable Machine Learn with Dask

https://github.com/dask/dask-ml/pulls?q=author:dsevero

Ward2ICU: A Vital Signs Dataset of Inpatients from the General Ward https://github.com/3778/Ward2ICU

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Independent Contractor

2018 - Current

Machine Learning Engineer & Researcher

Developed a Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources DataLake for running high volume machine learning models; Feature engineering and mathematical modeling for clustering algorithms used to segment patients into similar health groups; Ranked patients by future spendings using financial data achieving a precision at n=1,000 of 50% from a 15,000 total; Predicted patient LoS (Length of Stay) with regression techniques and hospital sensor data; Modified CoSimRank to create a similarity measure between developers and companies using Stack OverFlow data using Neo4j and Python.

Linx Impulse 2016 - 2018

Head of Data Science

Developed recommendation algorithms for E-commerce customers; Provided ad-hoc big data analyses to find insights from our data; Designed and monitored competitive A/B experiments devised to validate our systems performance in the face of competition; Internal A/B testing tool using the SciPy and Jupyter stack; Bandit algorithms for online optimization

Wavetech Technology Solutions

2015

Embedded Systems Engineering Intern.

Worked on microcontroller programming in C/C++ for cochlear implants.

CERTI Foundation

2010 - 2013 (Intern.)

Implemented signal processing routines (filter design $\,$

2015 - 2016 (R. Eng)

and realization) in C; Programmed back-end and front-end Python software for Raspberry Pi; Embedded eLua on a platform previously developed by CERTI.

WEG Industries

Summers 2011 and 2012

Electrical Engineering Intern.

Software upgrade, in LabVIEW, of an automatic calibrator of multimeters in order to account for different input frequencies; Conception and implementation of a hardware and software (LabVIEW) system that acquires, processes and stores data of specific parameters of electric motors.

REFERENCES

Prof. Ashish Khisti

University of Toronto

Professor and Canada Research Chair (Tier II)
Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering
https://www.comm.utoronto.ca/~akhisti/

Prof. Frank R. Kschischang

University of Toronto

Distinguished Professor of Digital Communication Department of Electrical & Computer Engineering https://www.comm.utoronto.ca/frank/

Prof. Danilo Silva

Federal University of Santa Catarina

Associate Professor Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering http://danilosilva.sites.ufsc.br/index.html

Prof. Chen Feng

The University of British Columbia

 $Assistant\ Professor \\ School\ of\ Engineering$

https://people.ok.ubc.ca/cfeng01/index.html